[WOMAN HUMMING
BAA. BAA. BLACK SHEEP SOFTLY]
[RAGGED BREATHING]
[CABINET DOOR CREAKS. CLOSES]
WOMAN: [SINGING] Baa. baa. black sheep
Have you any wool?
[RAGGED BREATHING CONTINUES]
Yes. sir. yes. sir. three bags full.
One for the master. one for the dame.
One for the little boy
Who lives down the lane.
Baa. baa. black sheep. have you any wool?
Yes. sir. yes. sir. three bags full
[SURREAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC FADES]
[KETTLE WHISTLING AND RATTLING]
[WHISTLING CONTINUES]
[SWITCH CLICKS]
[WHISTLING CONTINUES IN DISTANCE]
[BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[SWITCH CLICKS]
NARRATOR ON TV: …protected haven
of the mother's body
and entering the harsh. relatively cold.
danger-filled world outside
is inevitably more traumatic.
[WHISTLING STOPS]
The baby cow. whose mother has
to graze continuously for food.
- must be as developed as possible.
- [SWITCH CLICKS]
And is able to walk within hours.
[MUSIC PLAYS ON TV]
- And once...
- [TV CLICKS OFF]
[CHAIR CREAKS]
[SIGHS]
[CLOCK TICKING]
[AMBIENT NOISE GOES QUIET]
[LINE RINGING]
[CALL CONNECTS]
- JUSTIN: Oh. hello?
- Hey.
JUSTIN: [IN PLAYFUL TONE] Hello?
- [IN PLAYFUL TONE] Hello?
- H-H-Hello?
- [JUSTIN CHUCKLES]
- Hello?
- "Hello?" Okay. wait a sec. Just a sec.
- [CHUCKLES]
Hold on. hold on. Sorry. sorry.
One sec. [GRUNTS]
Um. how's your mom?
Uh. same.
Yeah. she hasn't eaten in two days and…
I'm sorry. Evy.
Yeah.
How are you holding up?
Um… [SIGHS]
I don't know.
I kinda just. um. want it to be over.
Is that bad to say?
No. no.
That's… Yeah. I understand it. Yeah.
Just wanna get out of here.
too. to be honest.
JUSTIN: What about Darren?
Like. where is he at?
Is he helping out at all?
- Uh. no. Not really.
- Okay. What's his number?
Like. can you text it to me?
'Cause I need to call this guy.
- He needs to step up.
- No. he…
He can barely take care of himself.
I don't even...
Well. at least drop off
some food. you know?
If he answers his phone.
I should've listened to you
a year ago. I know.
You know. I hate to say "I told you so"
but… I told you so.
How's you and Deb?
Uh. good. Yeah.
We're good.
We're thinking of getting a cat actually.
- Wow. Look at you.
- Yeah. [CHUCKLES]
Wait. I know what you need.
A lobotomy.
- [CHUCKLES] No.
- [LAUGHS]
- A Waterloo meatball sub.
- Oh. my…
That's the seventh…
I think you've said that
every day this week.
I guess I just miss it.
Then visit.
- It's been. what. ten years?
- Uh. five. first of all.
and you were out of town. remember?
You were going sicko mode in Punta Cana.
It was a wedding. Everyone drinks
at a wedding. I told you that.
Okay. well. you can visit too. you know?
Goes both ways.
I don't know.
I don't really have
any interest in London.
I'd mostly be going to see you.
[JUSTIN CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
Yeah.
You know. I could take some time off.
come help you out for a week.
No. No. no. no. Thank you.
- Really? You sure?
- No. I'm fine. I...
- I don't mind. 'Cause I could…
- Yeah. Yeah. No. totally.
- Okay.
- I'm fine. I really am.
Okay. We could also
skip this week if you want.
Are you kidding?
This is the only thing
keeping me sane right now.
Okay. 'cause that is so funny.
I was actually thinking
the exact opposite for me.
- [BOTH CHUCKLE]
- Like. some of these stories. man.
frickin' crazy.
If they were true.
You believed in some.
I could tell. okay?
- Like that one caller who...
- That's...
Hold on. That one caller who was addicted
to playing Ouija board by herself.
That's because that was true.
You saw the news clip.
A ghost didn't put her in that water tank.
The poor girl was depressed.
Who knows. all right? Who knows?
EVY: So what are we talking about
this episode?
You're gonna love this.
I got something juicy for you.
Ooh. do tell.
Let's wait until we start recording.
'cause I wanna get your
authentic reaction to this.
- Can't wait.
- Okay.
Oh. by the way. there's. like.
new intro and outro music.
I'm gonna use it for this episode.
Is that... That's cool?
- You wanna hear that?
- Uh. no. I'll just hear it in the edit.
I'm gonna play it anyway. Okay.
Uh. I'm ready to start recording
when you are.
[BUTTON CLICKS]
[PODCAST INTRO MUSIC PLAYING]
EVY: Welcome to another episode
of The Undertone Podcast
where we talk about all things creepy.
I'm your in-house skeptic. Evy Babić.
and I'm joined by my co-host.
and Santa Claus believer.
Justin Manuel.
JUSTIN: New episodes every Friday
anywhere you get your podcasts.
EVY: So without further ado.
Justin says he has
a real treat for us today.
- Tell us what it is. kiddo.
- [INTRO MUSIC ENDS]
JUSTIN: Uh. yeah. sure. "kiddo."
And for the record.
I never believed in Santa Claus.
not even when I was six years old. okay?
All my gifts said. "Made in China."
Everyone outsources. even Santa.
Okay. well. my house
didn't even have a chimney.
so how do you explain that?
Oh. that's easy.
He. um… He crawled in
through your mom's window.
- Oh!
- [BOTH CHUCKLE]
Wait a second. That explains
why I never saw Dad and Santa together
at those Christmas parties.
[LAUGHS]
Okay. So in our last episode.
we talked about the mysterious
"I Feel Wonderful" blog video
that allegedly caused 92 of its viewers
to kill themselves after watching it.
but not before slicing off their ears
and mailing them to the blog website's
headquarters in Palo Alto.
[UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
- Wait. Stop. Oh. my God. Evy.
- [BOTH CHUCKLE]
- What? It's fake.
- Stop. Can you please...
- It's been...
- Just stop it. please.
No. Justin. it's been debunked.
- Please.
- Okay. fine. You're no fun.
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
- [MUSIC STOPS]
- Did you stop it? I'm plugging my ears.
- It's…
- Okay.
- No. it's stopped.
- Okay. good.
- It's stopped.
Anyways. as I was saying.
after the last episode.
I was checking our podcast emails
and got a weird one
from an address I didn't recognize.
Their email was just
a bunch of random letters.
The subject line was "LOL" in caps.
And get this. ten audio files attached.
What did the message say?
Okay. It was just descending letters
and an upside-down smiley face.
Send it to me.
Uh. "please"?
- Please.
- Okay. Thanks.
[CHUCKLING] All right. Here you go.
Sent.
"Atonement at tenet." What does that mean?
Yeah. Beats me.
- Weird. Looks like a kid sent this.
- I know. right?
- Bet it's a virus.
- Okay.
That's what I thought too.
but then I said. "Screw it."
and I actually clicked the first file.
Brave.
What happened?
It was a phone recording
from a young couple.
and I listened for a bit.
and then I decided. you know.
save it for the podcast.
and we can play all ten of them together
and listen live.
Done. Yeah. Save it for the pod.
But first. let me put on
my logic and sanity hat.
Oh. right. the one I got you? All right.
So from what I gather.
the girlfriend's name is Jessa.
and I haven't heard
the boyfriend's name yet.
but let's have a listen to the whole file.
Okay. You ready?
- Ready.
- File number one. here we go.
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [STATIC]
[RUSTLING]
MAN: Um…
So. Jessa has been talking in her sleep
pretty much every night.
um. but she doesn't believe me.
so I'm going to record her.
JESSA: I do not talk in my sleep.
- MAN: You are talking right now…
- [JESSA LAUGHS]
…when you should be going to sleep.
JESSA: I… I…
I can't sleep with that thing on.
MAN: There.
JESSA: Let me see.
- It's still recording!
- MAN: No. it's not.
JESSA: [CHUCKLING] You're such a liar.
MAN: No. it's… Hey. babe. come on.
- I have an early morning. Let's...
- JESSA: Oh.
MAN: Let's get some sleep.
- Good night. baba.
- JESSA: Good night. ba.
[BOTH KISS]
[OBJECT CLACKS]
[MAN AND JESSA SIGH SLEEPILY]
JESSA: Can you just…
Can you tickle my head a little?
MAN: Sure.
[MAN SIGHS SLEEPILY]
JUSTIN: You know.
I see a little bump of sound
about four hours in.
Let's skip to that part.
JESSA: [SINGING] London bridge
Is falling down.
Falling down. falling down.
London Bridge is falling down.
My fair lady.
JUSTIN: Well. I guess that proves it.
She's not only talking in her sleep.
but singing in it. too.
The file goes on for a couple more hours.
but there's no big bumps.
So let's play file number two.
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [STATIC]
MAN: So. Jessa believes me now. and…
Uh…
JESSA: Babe. can you charge my phone?
MAN: Oh. sure.
[OBJECT CLACKING]
[JESSA AND MAN SIGH SLEEPILY]
JESSA: Good night.
MAN: Good night. baba.
JUSTIN: Okay. I'm gonna skip
to the bump in the waveform again.
[SHEET RUSTLING]
[BED CREAKS]
MAN: Jessa?
[MUSIC PLAYING DISTANTLY]
[MAN GRUNTS]
[RUSTLING AND CLATTERING]
[MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING DISTANTLY]
- [FOOTSTEPS]
- [STATIC CRACKLING]
[KIDS SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
Jessa?
What are you doing?
[MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING]
- [SOFT CLACK]
- [MUSIC SLOWS AND STOPS]
[SIGHS] Come back to bed.
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
- JUSTIN: That's it.
- Sleepwalking?
JUSTIN: Yeah. sounds like it.
What was she listening to?
It sounded like London Bridge
but in reverse.
JUSTIN: [CHUCKLES] Yeah. I thought so too.
Okay. Hold on.
I think I heard something else.
Let's play it back.
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
- [KIDS SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN: What are you doing?
- [SOFT CLACK]
- [MUSIC SLOWS AND STOPS]
[SIGHS] Come back to bed.
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
Uh. I couldn't hear anything.
What did you hear?
- JUSTIN: Uh. "The killer is out…"
- [CHUCKLES] What?
"Mike kill…"
[SINGS] Mike kill all. Mike kill all.
- Listen. I'm gonna play it again.
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
[LONDON BRIDGE PLAYS IN REVERSE]
- MAN: Jessa?
- [JUSTIN HUMS ALONG]
JUSTIN: [SINGS] Mike kill all.
MAN: What are you doing?
JUSTIN: Mike kill all
[SOFT CLACK]
- [MUSIC SLOWS AND STOPS]
[STATIC]
- [FEEDBACK SQUEALS]
- [JUSTIN EXCLAIMS]
EVY: Oh. fuck! Justin!
JUSTIN: Jesus. Sorry.
[SIGHS. GROANS]
EVY: It's fine.
JUSTIN: Well. let's get back
into character. [CLEARS THROAT]
- Okay.
- JUSTIN: So did you hear it?
Hear what?
"Mike kill all."
No. I didn't hear it.
Are you kidding? It's right there. Evy.
Uh. I don't doubt that you heard it.
but I would just chalk it up
to audio apophenia.
Uh. small words please. Evy.
You're creating meaning
from random sounds.
Okay. I can clearly
hear the words "Mike kill all."
It's a super old song.
Are you implying
there's hidden messages in it?
Oh. 'cause that's never happened before.
Let me just search
something up really quick.
Hold on.
Okay. Yeah. See?
Look. found something already.
Eleanor of Provence.
Queen Consort of England
in the Middle Ages.
She financed the construction
of the London Bridge.
and all nine of her
children died in childhood.
She feared that the bridge would collapse
if she didn't sacrifice children to it.
So she ordered the builders
to bury orphaned children alive
in the bridge's foundation.
EVY: You really believe that happened?
Well. she was the Queen Consort. Evy.
People would have to obey her
if they wanted to keep their heads.
Justin. any old children's song
can be interpreted in messed-up ways.
Like. Rock-a-bye Baby on the Tree Top?
The baby literally falls
to its death in that song.
You know what?
Do me a favor and search up
Baa. Baa. Black Sheep.
My mom used to sing
that to me when I was a kid.
[JUSTIN TYPING]
And found something.
Why am I not surprised?
Okay. So people have heard
a hidden message here. too.
So let's test this out ourselves.
see if we can hear it.
I'm downloading the song right now.
and I'm gonna play it in reverse.
Ready?
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [BAA. BAA. BLACK SHEEP PLAYS IN REVERSE]
- [MUSIC STOPS]
JUSTIN: Come on.
You're telling me you didn't hear that?
Not at all.
All right. Well. look.
I found an article on this song.
Baa. Baa. Black Sheep.
Okay. Spill it.
So it's apparently about a sheep farmer
whose sheep all turned out black.
but black wool was useless at the time
because it couldn't be dyed other colors.
So this farmer had
nothing to sell come winter.
And him and his family starved to death
until the villagers found his sheep
eating their bodies.
EVY: So all children's songs
are about children dying
and fucked up things happening to kids?
JUSTIN: Not even that. I think it's about
kids suffering for the things adults do.
But what's the point of it all?
Maybe to warn kids
that adults do messed up things.
and. uh. they should beware of them.
They're cautionary tales. right?
[SIGHS] I don't know.
Okay. Agree to disagree there.
Let's listen to the next one. all right?
File number three.
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [STATIC]
[WATER RUNNING]
- [MAN SNORING]
- JESSA: Mike?
- Mike?
- [MIKE GRUNTS]
Do you… Do you hear that?
[MIKE GRUNTS]
[JESSA WHIMPERS]
[MIKE SIGHING]
[WATER TRICKLING]
[BED CREAKS]
[MIKE SIGHS]
MIKE: Did you leave the water on?
[HIGH-PITCHED RINGING]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
- JUSTIN: His name is Mike!
Uh. Evy. "Mike kill all."
[UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING]
Um. yeah. can we take a break?
What? Yeah. sure.
I mean. yeah. no. what time is it?
Should we call it a night?
Um. continue tomorrow?
- Are you good?
- Yeah. yeah. yeah. I'm fine.
Oh. wait. actually I can't do tomorrow.
Uh. what about Tuesday?
Yeah. yeah. that works.
Um. sorry. can you. uh… can you send me
the Baa. Baa. Black Sheep song?
Sure. yeah.
You really didn't hear anything?
No. No. I didn't.
Weird. All right.
I'm gonna email it to you.
You should try slowing it down
and you'll hear it. I'm sure.
Yeah. okay. We'll see.
Okay. Night. Justin.
Good night.
- [CALL DISCONNECTS]
- [UNEASY MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MUSIC STOPS]
[CLOCK TICKING]
- [SOFT THUD]
- [SWITCH CLICKS]
[MAMA BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[LOW UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR CREAKING SOFTLY]
[SOFTLY] Hi. Mama.
Good night. Mama.
- [SWITCH CLICKS]
- [MUSIC STOPS]
MAMA: [OVER VOICEMAIL] Hi. Evy.
It's your mama.
Just calling to say hi.
I'm wondering if you're coming
to Mass tomorrow.
I haven't seen you in a while.
Anyway. I'm… I'm just calling you
to remind you.
You're Mama's little girl.
I'm praying for you.
Um. okay. talk soon.
[EVY RETCHING AND COUGHING]
[TOILET FLUSHES]
[WATER RUNNING]
EVY: Hi. this is Evangeline Babić.
I'd like...
No. no. she's fine. Um. thanks for asking.
No. I'd like to. um. make an appointment
for myself. actually.
Pregnancy test.
Yeah.
Yeah. I can come in tomorrow morning.
Thank you.
[WATER CONTINUES RUNNING]
[MAMA BREATHING AUDIBLY]
NURSE: Has she eaten
or drank anything today?
Yeah.
I mean. no. um. no. she…
[INHALES DEEPLY]
She hasn't eaten
for a few days now. [SIGHS]
NURSE: So as I explained before.
she was at a 50 for a month.
then at a 40 for weeks.
then at a 30 for days.
She's at a 20 now.
That's typically a sign
that it should be any day now.
Um…
So how will I know when it's time?
NURSE: You will hear
a rattling in her breath.
Death rattle.
NURSE: [SIGHS] Yes.
I don't like to call it that.
but that's the term.
Can she hear me?
NURSE: In this state.
no one can know for sure.
because there's no way to ask them.
But…
I like to believe they can.
[SURREAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[OBJECT CLACKS]
[FOOTSTEPS DEPART]
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
[DISQUIETING MUSIC PLAYING]
- Hey.
- DARREN: Hey.
Babe. uh… Uh. yeah.
I'm having a party at our place.
and I really think you should be there.
Why?
DARREN: Babe. you've been stuck
in that house for weeks.
Your mom's not going anywhere.
She'll be fine.
She's… She's just gonna sleep all night.
EVY: That's not it.
DARREN: I'm just trying
to do something for you.
and I don't really know
where we're at right now. but...
All right.
DARREN: Oh. Oh. okay.
Great. Can you be here at 8:30?
- Sure.
- DARREN: Okay. Awesome.
Well. don't worry about anything.
I've got everything covered.
Mm-hmm.
DARREN: Okay. Great.
Well. I'll see you soon. I love you.
Okay. Bye.
[CALL DISCONNECTS]
[DISQUIETING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MAMA BREATHING AUDIBLY]
- [HAIR DRYER WHIRRS. STOPS]
- EVY: Yes.
Well. tell them they can wait for me.
I waited for them.
I don't give a shit.
I'm a 40-minute drive away.
Fuck. I'll call you back.
[WATER SLOSHING]
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
[CELL PHONE CONTINUES BUZZING]
God!
[MAMA BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[SOFTLY] Mama?
I'm going out for a few hours.
I won't be long. okay?
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
Jesus.
I'll be back. Mama. Real quick.
[SWITCH CLICKS]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[DOOR OPENS. CLOSES]
[KEYS JINGLE]
[KEYS CLATTER]
[KEYS FALL]
[HANGS KEYS]
[KNOB CLICKS]
[CABINET DOOR CLOSES]
[CEREAL RUSTLING]
[WATER BOILING]
[CRUNCHING]
[UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
EVY: [GASPS] Mama!
[PANTING]
Mama.
Come on.
You scared me.
[KETTLE WHISTLING]
Okay.
[EVY GRUNTS. PANTING]
[WHISTLING CONTINUES]
[SIGHS]
I'm sorry. Mama.
- [PANTING]
- [WHISTLING CONTINUES]
[UNSETTLING MUSIC BUILDING]
- [WHISTLING AND MUSIC STOP]
- [MAMA BREATHES AUDIBLY]
[LOW SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUFFLED RHYTHMIC THUMPING]
[CLOCK TICKING]
[CHAIR CREAKS]
[AMBIENT NOISE GOES QUIET]
[BAA. BAA. BLACK SHEEP PLAYS IN REVERSE]
[PLAYBACK STOPS]
[EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
[BAA. BAA. BLACK SHEEP PLAYS IN REVERSE]
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
[EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [BAA. BAA. BLACK SHEEP PLAYS IN REVERSE]
- [RINGTONE PLAYING]
- [SIGHS]
- [CALL CONNECTS]
- Hello?
DR. RAM: Oh. uh. Evangeline. it's Dr. Ram.
Um. sorry for the hour.
I was gonna leave a voicemail.
Uh. no. it's okay. I'm up.
DR. RAM: Well. the results are in.
They've come back positive.
You're about six weeks.
Uh. I see.
DR. RAM: I can refer you
to an OB-GYN if you like.
No. um. I… I'd like to…
I'd like some time
to think about my options.
DR. RAM: Sure.
Yes. I… I understand. take your time.
Call the office whenever you're ready.
Thank you.
[CALL DISCONNECTS]
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
- [MUSIC STOPS]
- [WATER RUNNING]
[DISHES CLATTERING]
[WATER STOPS]
[MUFFLED THUDDING]
[WATER RUNNING IN DISTANCE]
[WATER CONTINUES RUNNING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[MAMA BREATHING AUDIBLY]
EVY: Mama?
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR LOCK CLICKS]
[SWITCH CLICKS]
[DOOR SQUEAKS. THUDS]
[MUSIC STOPS]
[MAMA BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING]
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
[BUZZING STOPS]
[SLURPING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[AMBIENT NOISE GOES QUIET]
MAMA: [OVER VOICEMAIL] Hi. Evy.
It's your mama. Just calling to say hi.
I'm wondering if you're coming
to Mass tomorrow.
I haven't seen you in a while.
Anyway. I'm… I'm just calling you
to remind you.
You're Mama's little girl.
I'm praying for you.
Um. okay. talk soon.
[UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING]
I'm praying for you. I'm praying for you.
I'm praying for you. I'm...
[MUSIC STOPS]
[EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
I'm praying for you.
I'm
[RINGTONE PLAYING]
- [CALL CONNECTS]
- Hello?
- JUSTIN: Hello?
Hey.
Hey. How… How's your mom?
Same. [SIGHS]
[SIGHS] I'm so sorry. Evy.
It's okay.
Is it?
I don't know.
I'm not. um… not really sleeping. so…
You're not drinking again. are you?
No.
Evy.
I'm not.
Okay. good.
Good. 'cause I don't want you
going backwards. you know?
Yeah. Well. I'm not. so…
Okay. Um. what are your plans after?
Are you back to Darren's?
Thinking of getting
my own place. actually.
Oh. really?
Yeah.
What about the house?
Can we just start? Let's start.
Sure. yeah. We can start.
Okay. let's do it.
So. where did we leave off.
the third recording?
Yes. and we heard
the sink filling up with water.
Right. yeah. How did it end?
Uh. Mike cut it short. the boyfriend.
What do you think happened there?
Let's just… let's save that
for the episode.
All right. all right. all right.
Well. I'm recording on my end.
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
- Recording.
Jesus. the faucet turned on by itself.
It's just an old house
with plumbing issues.
Could be. but let's keep
an open mind. Evy.
if that is possible for you.
Hey. I am open-minded.
I'm open to logic. I'm open to reason.
Okay. easy. easy. All right.
Let's play the next file.
maybe. uh. get some answers?
File number four.
Four of ten.
Let's do it.
Here we go.
[PLAYER BEEPS]
[STATIC]
[METAL CREAKS]
EERIE CHILD VOICE: Listen.
Do you hear something?
MIKE: What are you doing?
[METAL CREAKS]
EERIE CHILD VOICE:
I like it here in the dark.
MIKE: Put that back in the baby room.
JESSA: Why?
[METAL CREAKS]
EERIE CHILD VOICE:
I know something you don't.
MIKE: Oh!
JESSA: [CHUCKLES] What?
MIKE: I just... I don't know how
you could sleep with that thing.
JESSA: It's a Baby Sleep Time doll.
We all had one growing up.
MIKE: Put it back.
JESSA: No. she's sleeping with us tonight.
MIKE: No. fuck that. I…
Listen. if she's in here.
I'm gonna throw her out
when you're not looking.
[DOLL WINDS]
DOLL: Is everyone else asleep?
MIKE: [CHUCKLING]
Okay. okay. let's go to sleep.
[JESSA CHUCKLES]
JESSA: Okay. can you pass that bag?
MIKE: This plastic bag?
JESSA: No. no. so...
- Hold on. Pause it.
- JUSTIN: Mm? What's up?
I just emailed you something.
- Oh. okay.
- Play it.
Oh. my God.
- What? That's the doll?
- [DOLL WINDS]
DOLL: I like it here in the dark.
- [CHUCKLES] I know. right?
- [CHUCKLES] Oh. my God.
What kind of demented child wants
to sleep with that thing in their bed?
Yeah. I am shaking my head right now.
Anyway. they mentioned a baby room.
but there's no baby.
Yeah. I'm guessing they're expecting.
And. I mean. you think the baby's room
is where Jessa sleepwalks to?
That's my guess.
- Yeah. Hmm. Let's keep listening.
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
JESSA: It keeps moisture out.
so Baby Sleep Time stays nice and new.
Isn't that right. Baby Sleep Time?
MIKE: Mm-hmm.
[PLASTIC RUSTLING]
[JESSA AND MIKE SIGH SLEEPILY]
MIKE: Good night. baba.
JUSTIN: Skipping to the bump.
[BUTTON CLICKS]
[BANG]
- [INDISCERNIBLE WHISPER]
- [MIKE SNORING]
[BANG]
- JESSA: Mike?
- [MIKE GRUNTS]
- Do you hear that?
- [BANG]
[MIKE GROANS]
MIKE: What is that?
[BANG]
- [BANG]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
JUSTIN: That's the end of the file.
He stops it there.
That explains it.
That explains what?
The banging.
The water running.
It's faulty plumbing. It's an old house.
There was probably a blockage
in the pipes or something.
Hold on. hold on.
Just before the banging. you…
Did you hear something?
'Cause I heard something.
- What?
- It was pretty faint. It's like a voice.
I didn't hear anything.
Let me play it back louder.
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
- [STATIC]
[INDISCERNIBLE WHISPER]
[PLAYBACK STOPS]
JUSTIN: Yeah. there.
Did you… Did you hear that?
I did. What was that?
JUSTIN: I don't know.
I'm gonna play it louder.
[BUTTON CLICKS]
[STATIC]
- [INDISCERNIBLE WHISPER]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
JUSTIN: Oh. my… You heard that. right?
Tell me you heard that.
- Yes.
- Good. [CHUCKLES]
What's it saying?
Yeah. I can't really make it out.
I mean. it could be an artifact.
- an overlap of a previous recording.
- Mm.
I don't know.
I wonder if they noticed it
when they played it back.
Play the next one. Let's find out.
- Right. Okay. here we go.
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
[STATIC]
[BANG]
[JESSA MUMBLING]
- [BANG]
- MIKE: Jessa?
JESSA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
[BANG]
- [BANG]
- Uozyba-ni-emoc.
[BANG]
Uozyba-ni-emoc.
MIKE: Jessa. Jessa.
JESSA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
- Uozyba-ni-emoc.
- [BANG]
- MIKE: Jessa. what's wrong?
JESSA: Uozyba-ni-emoc!
- [BANGING CONTINUES]
- Uozyba-ni-emoc!
- MIKE: Jessa.
JESSA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
MIKE: Jessa.
JESSA: Uozyba… [SOBS]
MIKE: Jessa!
Jessa!
Babe. are you all right?
[JESSA SNIFFLES]
JESSA: Why are you looking
at me like that?
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
- [HIGH-PITCHED RINGING]
JUSTIN: What is happening?
- Evy? Hello?
- Um…
I… I… I think I need sleep.
I'm getting kinda loopy.
Oh. yeah. What time is it there?
Oh. shoot. I gotta go to work anyway.
Yeah. let's. uh…
let's record in a couple of days
like last time?
Okay. Yeah.
- Yeah. sounds good.
- Are you good?
- Mm-hmm.
- [DISTANT THUD]
[DISTANT THUD]
- What? What are you thinking?
Um… The artefact.
I'm gonna try and figure it out.
Okay. Um… [SNIFFS]
Yeah. All right.
Well. uh. rest up.
- Night. Justin.
- Yeah. Night. Evy.
[CALL DISCONNECTS]
[EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [MUSIC STOPS]
- [HEADPHONES CLACK]
[CLOCK TICKING]
[ELECTRICITY BUZZING]
[EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
[EERIE MUSIC INTENSIFIES]
[INDISTINCT WHISPERING]
[BUZZING CONTINUES]
[MAMA BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[BULB SCREW SQUEAKS]
[BUZZING STOPS]
Good night. Mama.
[SWITCH CLICKS]
[MAMA BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[SURREAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[DISHES CLATTERING]
[BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[WATER TRICKLES]
[MUSIC FADES]
Drink. Mama.
[PILLS RATTLING]
[RUSTLING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC INTENSIFIES. STOPS]
[AMBIENT NOISE GOES QUIET]
[MIKE SNORING]
[INDISCERNIBLE WHISPER]
[PLAYBACK STOPS]
[MIKE SNORING]
[INDISCERNIBLE WHISPER]
[PLAYBACK STOPS]
DEMONIC VOICE AND FEMALE VOICE:
Uozyba-ni-emoc.
Come in. Abyzou.
- Come in. Abyzou.
- [MOUTHING ALONG]
- Come in. Abyzou. Come in. Abyzou.
- [CONTINUES MOUTHING ALONG]
Come in. Abyzou.
Come in. Abyzou. Come in. Abyzou.
- Come in. Abyzou. Come in. Abyzou.
- [CLOCK TICKING]
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
[LIGHT CRACKLING]
[GASPS]
[EVY'S BREATH SHUDDERING]
[LIQUID DRIPPING]
[WHEEZING]
[VOCAL CLUCKING]
[CLUCKING INTENSIFIES]
[GASPS. PANTING]
[CLOCK TICKING]
[EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
[TICKING STOPS]
[DISTANT BANGING]
[JESSA MUMBLING]
MIKE: Jessa?
JESSA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
Uozyba-ni-emoc.
[BANGING CONTINUES]
MIKE: Jessa. Jessa.
JESSA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
Uozyba-ni-emoc.
MIKE: Jessa. what's wrong?
JESSA: Uozyba-ni-emoc!
Uozyba-ni-emoc!
- Uozyba-ni-emoc!
- MIKE: Jessa.
JESSA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
MIKE: Jessa.
JESSA: Uozyba… [SOBS]
MIKE: Jessa!
- Jessa!
- [JESSA SNIFFLES]
JESSA: Why are you
looking at me like that?
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
JUSTIN: Did you hear it?
No.
Are you serious?
It says. "Come in. Abyzou" in reverse.
Abyzou?
The taker of children.
[SCOFFS] Excuse me?
I looked up the name Abyzou.
It's the name of a demon
from Middle Eastern and European folklore.
She even appears in Christian texts
from the first century A.D.
in the Testament of Solomon.
Abyzou suffered from infertility.
making her envious of women
who could bear children.
She would sneak into the homes of mothers
and kill their newborn babies.
strangling them to death.
King Solomon had her hung in front
of the Temple of Jerusalem as punishment.
But her envy survived into the afterlife.
twisting her into a demon
who wandered the world
and caused miscarriages
and stillborn babies.
The most recent thing
I could find on Abyzou
came from the locals of Siquijor.
who believe that Abyzou entered a statue
of Saint Rita of Cascia.
the patron saint of cursed mothers.
Locals claimed that a woman
who worshiped the statue
killed her husband for cheating.
and then killed their baby.
and placed the baby's skull
with an inverted crucifix
in the statue's hands.
where they still are today.
according to tourists.
Okay. Okay. that's enough. [INHALES]
Let's just play the next one.
Are you okay. Evy?
Yeah. I'm fine. Just play it.
Are you sure?
Yes. [CHUCKLES] This is good stuff.
Let's get back into character.
- [CLEARS THROAT]
- [JUSTIN CLEARS THROAT]
"Come in. Abyzou." I heard it.
All of you listening heard it.
Now. let's get some answers.
- Playing the sixth file now.
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
[STATIC]
MIKE: [SIGHS] Um…
I just woke up.
and Jessa's still sleeping.
[JESSA YAWNING]
JESSA: Good morning.
MIKE: How'd you sleep?
JESSA: Slept like a baby.
[JESSA CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
MIKE: Did you dream anything?
JESSA: Nope. Why?
[MIKE SIGHS]
MIKE: You woke up from a nightmare.
JESSA: I don't remember.
MIKE: You were yelling in your sleep.
JESSA: Really? What… What was I saying?
MIKE: I don't know. Nonsense.
JESSA: Nonsense?
MIKE: Yeah. I… I have it all recorded.
JESSA: Let me hear it. [GRUNTS]
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
JUSTIN: That's it.
Wow. so she doesn't remember
anything at all.
Interesting.
Speaking in reverse. not remembering it.
That's eerily consistent with...
Before you say it. let me guess.
[IN DEEP VOICE] Demonic possession.
- Okay. it's not a joke. Evy.
- [CHUCKLES]
There are church-documented cases
of possessions
dating back centuries.
not just in Roman Catholic doctrines.
but in Islam...
- [IN NORMAL VOICE] Yeah. Yeah. of course.
- Judaism...
They were documented centuries ago.
This is before people knew
about mental illnesses
like psychosis. schizophrenia.
So you think psychosis
can cause someone to speak in reverse?
Unconsciously. yeah.
Okay. that's a stretch.
Something she read before.
stuck in her subconscious.
- Wait. Oh. my God. What?
- What?
Okay. I'm just looking
at this waveform on the file.
When she's saying it.
there's. like. a parallel pattern.
What are you talking about?
There's. like. two different
voices overlapping when she's saying it.
- Oh. come on. [CHUCKLES]
- No. it's right in front of me.
Graphically. I can see it.
Well. I'm no engineer.
and neither are you.
Okay. Well. let's just keep listening
and get some answers.
- Playing the file now.
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
MIKE: Okay. So. it's 9:02 p.m.
JESSA: Mike. did you see
my bags for my dolls?
MIKE: No. Why?
JESSA: Baby is out of her bag.
I don't know where the bag is.
MIKE: [SIGHS] She'll survive one night.
- [BED CREAKING]
- [BOTH GRUNTING]
Good night. baba.
JESSA: Good night. ba.
[BOTH KISS]
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
- JUSTIN: Okay. I'm skipping to the bump.
[SHEET RUSTLING]
[BED CREAKS]
- [MIKE SNORING SOFTLY]
- [FOOTSTEPS]
[BABY CRYING]
[MIKE GASPS]
MIKE: Jessa?
- [BABY CRYING]
- [MIKE GRUNTS SOFTLY]
What the fuck?
[BED CREAKING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[JESSA SCREAMING]
MIKE: Jessa!
- [FOOTSTEPS RUNNING]
- [MIKE PANTING]
- Jessa. What... What is it?
- [JESSA CRYING]
- JESSA: In the sink.
- [MIKE PANTING]
MIKE: What is it? There's nothing in here.
JESSA: [WAILING] There was a baby…
MIKE: What?
[JESSA SOBBING]
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
[GASPS SOFTLY]
JUSTIN: A baby crying?
The neighbor's baby.
All right. I promised myself
I wasn't gonna email this guy.
You're replying to the email?
Yeah. I just did.
What'd you say?
- Uh. I just asked. "Who are you?"
- [NOTIFICATION CHIMES]
And. um…
- What happened?
- Oh. no. it just bounced back.
"Mail delivery subsystem.
Address not found."
Deleted his account. I guess.
- Wait. hold on a sec. The…
- What?
The email address. the random letters.
they're. um…
It's actually… it's "Come in. Abyzou"
spelled backwards.
[CHUCKLES LIGHTLY] Clever.
Snap out of it. Justin.
There's just three files left.
Play the next one.
- Jesus.
- Come on.
- Yeah.
- Let's hear it. We're almost at the end.
[SIGHS] Okay.
- Okay.
- Yeah. okay. All right.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Um. this is audio file number eight.
[PLAYER BEEPS]
[MIKE SNORING SOFTLY]
[SHEET RUSTLES]
[BANG]
JESSA: Mike?
[MIKE SIGHS SOFTLY]
JESSA: [TEARFULLY] Mike.
[MIKE GROANS]
- [BANG]
- [MIKE SHUSHES]
MIKE: [PANTS] Stay here.
[BANG]
JESSA: Mike. Mike. no.
don't leave me here!
- [MIKE BREATHING HEAVILY]
- [BANG]
[LOUD BANG]
KIDS: [SINGING]
Baa. baa. black sheep. have you any wool?
-Yes. sir. yes. sir. three bags full
-[MUSIC PLAYING OVER RECORDING]
One for the master. one for the dame.
One for the little boy
Who lives down the lane.
Baa. baa. black sheep. have you any wool?
Yes. sir. yes. sir. three bags full.
Baa. baa. black sheep have you any wool?
One for the master. one for the dame.
One for the little boy who lives...
[STATIC CRACKLES. SCRATCHING RHYTHMICALLY]
- [SOFT CLICK]
- [STATIC STOPS]
[BABY CRYING]
MIKE: Fuck.
Where the fuck is that coming from?
- [JESSA SCREAMING]
- Jessa!
- [MIKE PANTING]
- [JESSA CRYING]
Jessa. Jessa.
[SOFTLY] Hey. hey. hey.
Hey. hey. hey.
- [MIKE'S BREATH SHUDDERING]
- [JESSA CRYING]
JESSA: I saw… I saw her. [WAILING]
MIKE: Who. who. who?
JUSTIN: Evy?
[JESSA CRYING]
Evy?
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
JUSTIN: Baa. Baa. Black Sheep?
[SIGHS SOFTLY]
It was a coincidence.
Evy. it was the same version.
Coincidences happen.
I mean. they're rare.
but that's why we get
so surprised when they happen.
I just feel... This feels different to me.
Hold on.
What?
I'm searching "Come in. Abyzou"
spelled backwards.
Why?
Justin?
Yeah. I'm still here.
- Jesus.
- What?
There's a study.
A psychologist treated
two separate patients
who were fixated
on "Come in. Abyzou" spelled backwards.
One spent days texting it
to random numbers
before drowning
her nine-month-old daughter
in the kitchen sink.
What the…
The other was a ceramic artist.
She was admitted to the hospital
after making hundreds
of figurines of dead children.
giving them away to young women
around her neighborhood
before committing suicide in the hospital.
She was five months pregnant.
[EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
You there?
Yeah.
What do we do?
I… I think we should stop listening.
- Just trash this episode.
- What?
Skip this week.
Why would we trash it?
We're onto something good.
I just feel like
we're playing with fire or...
We have to keep listening.
No. people are gonna eat this shit up.
It's really good.
We just. um. stop it here.
make this episode two parts.
publish on Friday.
record part two next week.
[JUSTIN SIGHS WEARILY]
Okay. Okay. yeah.
Okay. Let's record the outro.
Okay.
- Ready?
- Yeah. let's. uh. get back into character.
[JUSTIN CLEARS THROAT]
Join us next week
where we continue listening
to the last two audio files.
Jessa speaking backwards in her sleep.
faucets turning on by themselves.
loud banging. baby crying.
Can all of this be explained
or is there something
more sinister underneath it all?
[CHUCKLES] You'd love that. wouldn't you?
[SIGHS SOFTLY]
So join us next Friday.
A conclusion to the mystery…
Or just more questions.
Uh. no. Every story has an ending.
This is it. I feel it.
It ends next episode.
[HIGH-PITCHED RINGING]
Uh. if anyone out there
listening has any idea what's going on
or. uh. might have some idea
who Mike and Jessa might be.
please call us during our live recording
this Monday from 2:30 a.m.
to 3:30 a.m.. Eastern Time.
Until then. this is Justin.
EVY: And this is Evy.
JUSTIN: And remember.
don't be afraid of the dark.
Be afraid of the silence.
[RECORDING STOPS]
[BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[SOFTLY] Mama. can you hear me?
Your little girl's pregnant.
I wanted to name her Mary.
Remember how you used to pray
those Hail Marys for me every night?
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Mama…
[BREATHING AUDIBLY]
Only…
I don't think I'm fit to be a mama. Mama.
[SWITCH CLICKS]
[UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
[FAINT CREAKING]
- [DOOR CREAKS]
- [LOCK CLICKS]
[BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[SURREAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[PILLS RATTLING]
[WATER RUNNING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[SWITCH CLICKS]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[SURREAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC FADES]
- [SERENE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [SIGHS]
[BELLS CHIME SOFTLY]
WOMAN: [OVER EARPHONES] Welcome
to this guided sleep meditation.
[WATER RIPPLING]
I'd like you to imagine
that you're standing
at the edge of a quiet lake.
The moonlight glitters on its surface.
Barefoot. you step into the shallow water.
The water feels warm on your skin.
Looking down. you see something
floating up from the water's depths.
[EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
A little tiny thing.
bloated and pale.
rising to the surface.
What is it?
The bobbling twirl in the stain.
DUAL VOICES: Whirling toddlers
down the spin.
Tickle there. girl.
Wretched wheezing. The choking children.
WOMAN AND DEMONIC VOICE:
Dancing penance. Weeping here.
Bleeding whore. Wobble out.
Cupboard the muck. The slut.
[IMPERCEPTIBLE SCREAMING]
[SCREAMS]
[GASPS]
- WOMAN: A gentle breeze…
- [BELLS CHIME]
…pushes more ripples
across the still water…
[WATER RIPPLING]
…and rustles the leaves around you.
So peaceful. so...
MAMA: [WHISPERING IN DISTANCE]
Blessed art thou amongst women
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb. Jesus.
Holy Mary. Mother of God.
pray for us sinners.
now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
Holy Mary. Mother of God.
pray for us sinners.
Now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
Pray for us sinners.
now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
- [SWITCH CLICKS]
- [BREATHING AUDIBLY]
Mama?
What did you say?
Mama. I know you said something.
I know you were talking. Mama. answer me!
Why won't you answer me?
[SOFTLY] I'm sorry. Mama.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Hi. this is Evangeline Babić calling.
Um. if you can give me
a call back. please?
I was hoping to get a referral
to the women's clinic.
if you can. Um…
Thank you. Please give me a call back.
[MAMA BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[SWITCH CLICKS]
[FOOTSTEPS DEPARTING]
[BREATHING AUDIBLY]
[BREATHING RAGGEDLY]
[WHEEZING]
[WHEEZING FADES]
[VOCAL CLUCK]
EVY: Welcome to another episode
of The Undertone Podcast.
I'm your host. Evy Babić.
and I'm joined
by my co-host. Justin Manuel.
New episodes every Friday
anywhere you get your podcasts.
JUSTIN: And if you missed
our last episode.
you should really go back
and have a listen.
All right. so we have heard
eight out of ten
of these mysterious audio recordings
from an anonymous email.
There's only two left.
And before we dive in.
I just want to give a heads-up.
Since we started this journey.
we've heard some deeply unsettling stuff.
There have been voices. babies crying.
even what sounds like
a real demonic possession.
All of it leading back to one name.
Abyzou.
So if you're still listening.
maybe think twice.
because there might not be
any turning back
after this week's episode.
[LAUGHS]
What?
"No turning back"?
- Yeah. I mean...
- Justin.
- The last recording we heard…
- Please.
- …what the hell was that?
- Are you serious?
Uh…
Were we not listening to the same thing?
Uh. yeah. we were. [SCOFFS]
There was obviously only one explanation.
Which is?
It was a hoax.
What?
"A hoax"?
- They're attention-seekers.
- Huh. yeah.
They obviously staged the whole thing
and then sent it to us.
They probably changed their names.
There's no way this is fake.
No way. No way.
- Whatever.
- [JUSTIN CLEARS THROAT]
Last episode.
I invited listeners to call us
with any information they might have
on Mike and Jessa.
So some calls might be
coming in live during this recording.
Are you ready. Evy?
I've been ready all week.
[CHUCKLES LIGHTLY]
Same.
So file number nine.
After this. there's only one file left.
Here we go.
[PLAYER BEEPS]
[JESSA CRYING]
JESSA: I don't feel good.
MIKE: What's wrong?
JESSA: [TEARFULLY] I remember last night.
I woke up. I couldn't move.
You weren't beside me.
It was someone else.
A shadow.
And so I prayed Hail Mary.
but then the shadow…
The shadow started praying. too.
[JESSA LAUGHING]
It was mocking me. [LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
MIKE: Okay. Okay.
[LAUGHTER DISTORTS]
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
JUSTIN: Sorry about that. folks.
That… That wasn't a playback error.
The. uh. audio file is corrupted.
so it just ends there.
That was short.
Wait. what's... What is going on?
What?
The time on my laptop.
it's showing 20 to 3:00.
- but it should be 20 to 9:00.
- [CLOCK TICKING]
A glitch in the matrix?
[RINGTONE PLAYING]
Oh. we got our first caller.
ladies and gents.
Oh. the caller's from your area code. Evy.
Hello. this is The Undertone Podcast.
You're being recorded live.
Hello? Hello?
BOY: Oh. Yeah.
Hey. Is this The Undertone?
JUSTIN: Yes.
Uh. where are you calling from?
BOY: Oh. um. I'm calling from Westerland.
JUSTIN: Ooh. Do you know an Evy?
Yeah. Justin. everyone
from Westerland knows each other.
[JUSTIN CHUCKLES]
JUSTIN: Uh. so what do you got
for us. caller?
BOY: Mike and Jessa.
they were my neighbors.
They lived just down the street from me.
JUSTIN: You…You know them?
BOY: Not well. but I recognize
their voices and their names.
and it makes sense now
what happened to them.
JUSTIN: "What happened to them"?
BOY: They died. The police found them
at the bottom of the stairs
with plastic bags on their heads
and dead babies drawn all over the walls.
JUSTIN: And… And you're sure this is the
same Mike and Jessa we're talking about?
BOY: Yeah. it's them.
Jessa. she was five months pregnant.
- Hey. what street did you live on?
- [STATIC]
JUSTIN: Wait. hello?
- Hello?
- JUSTIN: You're… You're cutting out.
- Wait. wait. wait. Hello?
- [CALL DISCONNECTS]
They died. That's awful.
[RINGTONE PLAYING]
Hi. Sorry. you cut out.
You were… You were saying?
WOMAN: What?
JUSTIN: Oh. Nothing.
WOMAN: This is Undertone. right?
JUSTIN: Uh. yes. Yes.
Where are you calling from?
WOMAN: San Diego.
JUSTIN: Okay.
And do you have any information
about Mike and Jessa?
WOMAN: No. not them.
but a lady. a crazy lady
that used to rent our basement.
JUSTIN: Okay. go on.
WOMAN: She would play music
every night in reverse.
JUSTIN: In… In reverse?
WOMAN: Yes.
JUSTIN: Really? What… What song?
WOMAN: I don't know.
Sounded like kids singing backwards.
JUSTIN: And what happened to the…
to the lady?
WOMAN: She was arrested.
Last I heard. she was in prison.
- It was fucked up.
- JUSTIN: Arrested for… for what?
WOMAN: Killing her baby.
We all heard this loud. hollow banging
coming from the vents over and over.
And my dad. he went down to check.
And the lady. she was swinging
a garbage bag against the furnace.
My daddy stopped her
and he looked inside the bag.
and then at the bottom. it was her baby.
[CRAYON SNAPS]
JUSTIN: That's awful.
What... What was the...
What was the woman's name?
WOMAN: I don't remember.
I was just a kid when it happened.
It's messed up. I'm sorry.
I hope it helps.
JUSTIN: No. no. this is. um…
this is good info. yeah.
No. definitely. Thank you.
WOMAN: Will I be in the next episode?
JUSTIN: Absolutely.
Yeah. thanks for calling.
WOMAN: Thank you. man.
JUSTIN: Um…
[LAUGHS]
What are you laughing at?
You believe that?
Yeah. Why… Why wouldn't I?
People love hearing
the sound of their own voice.
especially on a podcast. [SNIFFLES]
- Okay. but the email. it...
- What about the email?
I don't know. What if it…
- What if tenet means...
- What?
Ten. the tenth file? I don't know.
- What if it was a warning?
- Well. then let's play it.
There's only one way to find out.
I don't... I don't want to.
Justin. it's too late. Play it.
All right. Okay. yeah. You know what?
I'm just gonna... I'm gonna click play
before I change my mind.
Good.
File number ten. here we go.
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [STATIC]
JESSA: She's listening.
MIKE: Hmm?
Baba?
JESSA: She's listening.
MIKE: Jessa?
- You're burning up.
- JESSA: She's listening.
MIKE: Hey. hey. get up.
I'm gonna have to take you to a hospital.
JESSA: No. No. I need to warn her.
MIKE: What... What are you saying?
JESSA: She's listening.
[SOBS] She's listening.
MIKE: Jessa. we have to get out of here.
JESSA: I have to warn her!
- MIKE: No. Jessa. wait!
- [BANGING]
[GRUNTS] Jessa. where are you going?
- [BANGING CONTINUES]
- [MIKE PANTING]
- Jessa!
- [HURRIED FOOTSTEPS]
[LOUD HOLLOW BANGING]
[RATTLY BREATHING]
MIKE: Jessa?
[LOUD BANGING CONTINUES]
[VOCAL CLUCK]
JESSA: Look and lick
all the blood off now.
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
[VOCAL CLUCK]
[BREATHES SHAKILY]
Wait. there should be more.
Did you touch something?
JUSTIN: No. No. no. no.
It… It stopped. It stopped by itself.
I'm pressing play. it won't play.
[TICKING]
We should stop listening.
- [STATIC BLASTS]
- Justin!
JUSTIN: I didn't touch anything. I… I…
[BAA. BAA. BLACK SHEEP PLAYING IN REVERSE]
[EVY SHUDDERING]
[MUFFLED BANGING]
MIKE: Jessa.
[BANGING CONTINUES]
- MIKE: Jessa!
- [GASPS HOARSELY]
- [JESSA SCREAMING]
- MIKE: Jessa!
- [MIKE PANTING]
- [JESSA SOBBING]
- Jessa! Jessa!
- [ELECTRICITY BUZZING]
Jessa.
KIDS: [SINGING]
Baa. baa. black sheep. have you any wool?
- Yes. sir...
- [BULB POPS]
- [SONG STOPS]
- [MIKE PANTING]
JESSA: Something's wrong. Justin.
- I'm so cold.
- [BABY COOS]
[SHUDDERING]
MIKE: Where the fuck is that coming from?
[BABIES CRYING]
[WHIMPERING]
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [PLAYBACK STOPS]
JUSTIN: She said my name.
[PANTING]
She said. "Justin."
It was you.
No. Evy. no. What?
- You're behind this. aren't you?
- I wouldn't do that. Evy. I...
[RAISES VOICE] Is this funny to you?
[RINGTONE PLAYING]
Wait. Hello?
WOMAN 2: I'd like to speak with Mary.
JUSTIN: There's no Mary here. I...
- [MUFFLED BANGING]
- JUSTIN: I…
- WOMAN 2: I'd like to speak with Mary.
- [LOUD BANG]
JUSTIN: [SHAKILY] Who is this?
WOMAN 2: I'd like to speak with Mary.
JUSTIN: Who is this?
I'd like to speak with Mary.
JUSTIN: Evy?
WOMAN 2: I'd like to speak with Mary.
I'd like to speak with Mary.
- I'd like to speak with Mary.
- Justin. hang up!
DEMONIC VOICE: I'd like
to speak with Mary.
[CALL DISCONNECTS]
- JUSTIN: Oh. no. I… I feel…
- [RINGTONE PLAYING]
WOMAN 3: [LAUGHS] The Undertone?
JUSTIN: Yes.
WOMAN 3: You shouldn't
have called out to her.
JUSTIN: [SHAKILY] Who? Who?
WOMAN 3: Abyzou.
She waits in the tenth file
at the witching hour.
You shouldn't have
listened to all of them.
JUSTIN: Listened... Listened to…
WOMAN 3: What were you thinking?
DEMONIC VOICE: What were you thinking?
[WOMAN 3 LAUGHING]
JUSTIN: Wait. Wait. wait.
- [WOMAN 3 CONTINUES LAUGHING]
- [EERIE MUSIC BUILDS. STOPS]
WOMAN 3: She…to…lick all
the blood off her fingers.
- [STATIC]
- [CALL DISCONNECTS]
JUSTIN: [SHUDDERING]
She's gone. She's gone.
- Evy.
- [RINGTONE PLAYING]
[CALL CONNECTS]
- [BABY CRYING]
- JUSTIN: Hello? Hello?
WOMAN 4: I don't know what to do.
JUSTIN: Okay.
WOMAN 4: I'm no good.
JUSTIN: What? What?
WOMAN 4: I don't know what I'm doing.
JUSTIN: What are you... What are you doing?
What are you doing?
WOMAN 4: Can you help me?
JUSTIN: Yeah.
Okay. Evy. Evy. I don't...
WOMAN 4: He won't stop crying.
[BABY CRYING]
My poor baby.
JUSTIN: Who... Who am I speaking with?
WOMAN 4: Abby.
- Can you help me?
- JUSTIN: Yeah. of course.
We can… We can help you.
Right? Right. Evy?
ABBY: How do I stop him from crying?
JUSTIN: Abby.
- Where are you calling us from?
- ABBY: Don't worry. baby.
- I'll make it stop.
- [CRYING INTENSIFIES]
- [PLASTIC RUSTLING]
- JUSTIN: What are you doing. Abby?
ABBY: It'll all be better soon.
my little one.
- JUSTIN: Abby.
- Abby. stop!
JUSTIN: Ab...
ABBY: She's safe now.
JUSTIN: Abby. call...
ABBY: Everything's gonna be okay.
JUSTIN: Call 911 right now. Abby. hang up
- and call 911 right now.
- No. no. no. Abby. we can help you.
- JUSTIN: Evy.
- What's your address?
Can you tell me your address?
ABBY: [SOBBING] I'm no good.
I'm saving her.
[BABY CONTINUES CRYING]
Abby?
- ABBY: I'm no good. I'm no good.
- [PLASTIC RUSTLING]
You are good. Abby. You're good.
[ABBY SOBBING]
Do you hear me?
Abby. Talk to me.
[BABY CONTINUES CRYING]
I killed my mother.
[CRYING STOPS]
My mommy.
ABBY: What?
When I was young.
she used to pray
by my bedside every night.
Every single night.
And when she got really sick.
she asked me to pray with her
every single night.
And I said I couldn't
because I was too busy. tired.
But it wasn't true.
She stopped eating.
and she stopped talking.
It was too late.
I killed my mother.
[ABBY SOBBING]
- [BABY CRYING]
- You are good. Abby.
You're good.
ABBY: How do you know?
Because I believe it.
I believe it. Abby.
[ABBY SOBBING]
- [BABY CONTINUES CRYING]
- [ABBY SOBBING SORROWFULLY]
Abby?
- [ABBY SOBBING]
- [BABY CRYING]
[ABBY LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
[PLASTIC RUSTLING]
DEMONIC VOICE: It's too late.
- [BANG]
- JUSTIN: Oh. my fucking God.
- [ABBY LAUGHING]
- Oh. my fucking God.
Trace the call. Justin!
JUSTIN: Oh. my fucking God. Oh. my God.
- [BANG]
- Where's my phone? Where's my...
- [STATIC CRACKLING]
- I don't... I… I…
[BAA. BAA. BLACK SHEEP PLAYS IN REVERSE]
Jesus Christ.
[DEMONIC VOICE LAUGHING]
Evy. I… Hello?
- [BANGING]
- Evy. can you hear me?
Evy... Hello?
Wait. Evy. I can't... I can't...
I can't hear you. I can't...
Hello? Hello?
[SONG STOPS]
- [BANGING]
- [SHOUTING] Evy. where are you?
Oh. my God!
Evy! Evy!
[SURREAL EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
KID: [OVER RECORDING] I wanna listen
to Baa. Baa. Black Sheep.
[CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY]
[EERIE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[LOUD HOLLOW BANGING]
[BUTTON CLICKING]
[THUMPING]
[SHUDDERING]
[ABBY LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
[BANGING]
- [PLASTIC RUSTLING]
- [MUFFLED LAUGHTER]
MAMA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
- JUSTIN: Get out of the house.
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
EVY: I killed my mother.
JUSTIN: Evy. get out of the house.
DEMONIC VOICE: I'd like
to speak with Mary.
JUSTIN: Get out of the house. Evy.
EVY: I killed my mother.
DEMONIC VOICE: I'd like
to speak with Mary.
EVY: I killed my mother.
MAMA: I'm praying for you.
EVY: My mommy.
JESSA: [LAUGHING] It was mocking me.
- [LOUD BANGING]
- [JESSA LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
[WATER RUNNING]
[CABINET DOOR CREAKS. KNOCKS]
- [KETTLE WHISTLING]
- [LAUGHTER STOPS]
[PANTING]
DOLL: Listen… can you hear something?
[EERIE INDISTINCT WHISPERING]
EVY: Your little girl's pregnant.
I wanted to name her Mary.
Remember how you used to pray
those Hail Marys for me every night?
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
Only I don't think I'm fit to be a mama…
[BULBS POP AND SHATTER]
[BULB POPS AND SHATTERS]
Justin!
- [CHANDELIER CREAKING]
- [DISQUIETING MUSIC PLAYING]
Justin!
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [MAMA SCREAMS]
JUSTIN: Evy. Evy. I'm here.
I'm here. I'm here.
- I'm here. I'm here.
- What is this?
MAMA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
- Uozyba-ni-emoc.
- JUSTIN: I'm gonna…
- MAMA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
- What the fuck is this?
MAMA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
JUSTIN: I'm gonna help.
I'm gonna go… I'm gonna go help.
- MAMA: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
- No. no. no. don't leave me!
- Uozyba-ni-emoc.
- I don't know what to do. I can't help.
- [VOCAL CLUCK]
- MAMA: Uozyba-ni-emoc!
[INTENSIFYING] Uozyba-ni-emoc!
Uozyba-ni-emoc!
- Uozyba-ni-emoc!
- [RAPID SCRATCHING]
Uozyba-ni-emoc!
[SCRATCHING CONTINUES]
[RAPID RAGGED PANTING]
[FEROCIOUS PANTING]
[INDISCERNIBLE WHISPERING]
[EERIE MUSIC BUILDS]
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
- [MUSIC STOPS]
[AMBIENT NOISE GOES QUIET]
[LOW RUMBLING]
- [PLASTIC RUSTLES]
- [GAGS]
[ELECTRICITY BUZZING SOFTLY]
[GAGS]
[STATIC CRACKLING]
[EERIE MUSIC BUILDING]
[BULB POPS AND SHATTERS]
[SURREAL EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
[EERIE MUSIC INTENSIFYING]
- Mama!
- [BULB SHATTERS]
[MUSIC STOPS]
[FOOTSTEPS]
- [MAMA TUMBLING]
- [EVY SCREAMING]
- EVY: Mama!
- [VOCAL CLUCKING]
[WAILING] Mama!
No! No! No!
- Mama!
- [CLUCKING CONTINUES]
Mama!
- [EVY SOBBING]
- [SOFT FOOTSTEPS]
- Justin!
- [CLUCKING CONTINUES]
Justin!
[BABIES CRYING]
- [EVY WHIMPERING]
- [CLUCKING CONTINUES]
[DOOR OPENS]
- [EVY PANTING]
- [BABIES CONTINUE CRYING]
EVY: Something's wrong. Justin.
EVY AND DEMONIC VOICE: I'm so cold.
DEMONIC VOICE: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
EVY: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
[BABIES CONTINUE CRYING]
DEMONIC VOICE: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
EVY: Uozyba-ni-emoc.
- Come in. Abyzou.
- [PLAYER BEEPS]
[CRYING STOPS]
[LONDON BRIDGE IS FALLING DOWN
INSTRUMENTAL PLAYING]
[MUSIC SLOWS]
[MUSIC SLOWING AND DISTORTING]
[MUSIC CONCLUDES]
[EERIE SURREAL MUSIC PLAYING]